Railroad Files 6039
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Railroad Files
1862-1979
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
6039
5.67 cubic feet
5.7 linear ft.
Records.
8407043
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 13, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6039 mb: Railroad Memorabilia
8407043
- Train service time books for different workers during years, 1912-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Map of the railroads in New York State, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pay Roll sheet from Lawton Branch Rail Road Co., 1864 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  May 1864
- Rules & Regulations of Branch No. - United Trainmen's Association, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Instituted at St. Thomas, Jan. 7, 1883, St. Thomas. Ont.
- "Firing Locomotives: A Practical Treatise on Combustion and Steam Making", by Angus Sinclair (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Sheahan's telegraphic cipher code, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  1938 edition
- St. Louis, Iron Mountain & Southern Railway Co. -- Way-Bill (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Financier's Office - Brotherhood of Railroad Brakemen - Quarterly Report, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  May 31, 1888
- Payroll for Boston & Providence Rail Road, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  May, 1863
- Pullman's Palace Car Company - Pullman Palace, Pacific & Southern Car Companies - Pullman's Palace Car Company, General Ticket Dept., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Ticket/May 22, 1883; General ticket - Chicago/188-; Chicago, April 24th, 1883
- Xerox copy of payroll for Mobile & Ohio RR, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  April, 1862
- Railroad Man's Guide (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 2 Train orders on New York, Lake Erie & Western Railroad (former ERIE), 1890 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  March 12, 1890
- Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Co. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Clearance Cards -- Train Orders -- Freight Receipts
- Cipher Code for use of Organizations of Railway Employees in Telegraphic Correspondence, arranged by Sheahan, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Rule and Specifications for Uniforms / Chicago, St. Paul, Minneapolis & Omaha Railway Company, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  effective January 1, 1921
- Pennsylvania Lines: West of Pittsburgh Western Division; Regulations and Rates of Pay Governing Conductors, Trainmen and Yardmen, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  effective September 1, 1910
- Pennsylvania Rail Road Co. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Instructions governing employment of women for rail road service on the Pennsylvania Rail Road
- Union Pacific Railroad, Golden Spike Centennial (Box 1, Folder 19)
  kit containing: 1 pamphlet ("the Union Pacific Story"); 6 smaller booklets; 6 photographs
- NY Central; Pittsburgh & Lake Erie Rail Road (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Charts & history of the Rail road
- "Pay Roll of Force employed in the Transportation of Passengers and Merchandise on the Bristol Line, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  April, 1868
- Union Pacific "City of Los Angeles -- The Challenger" (Box 1, Folder 22)
  trip description, schedules, train information
- Joint Way-Bill for Galveston, Houston & Henderson Rail Road, from Galveston to Grand Rock, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Dec. 2, 1882
- "The Story of the Centenary Pageant of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company", R.D. Form 4-B - from the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Answers to examination questions dated June 25th, 1920
- Lehigh Valley Railroad Company (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Correspondence; Copy of original strike order announced by the American Railway Union against the Great Northern Railway; other misc. papers regarding the strike order
- Cipher Code for use of Organizations of Railway Employees, in Telegraphic correspondence, arranged by Sheahan, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  2nd edition
- Boston & Providence Railroad Corporation -- Machinery Department Pay Roll, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Mitchell's Models and easy lessons in locomotive running (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Westinghouse No. 6 Distributing Valve E T Locomotive Brake Equipment
- Mitchell's Models and easy lessons in locomotive running (Box 1, Folder 29)
  S-6 Independent Brake Valve; No. 6 E T Locomotive Brake Equipment
- Mitchell's Models and easy lessons in locomotive running (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Westinghouse Type K Triple Valve
- Mitchell's Models and easy lessons in locomotive running (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Westinghouse Type L Triple Valve
- Mitchell's Models and easy lessons in locomotive running (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Train Air-Signal System
- Mitchell's Models and easy lessons in locomotive running (Box 1, Folder 33)
  H-6 Automatic Brake Valve, No. 6 E T Locomotive Brake Equipment
- Seaboard Coast Line Railroad, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  passenger schedule booklet, effective April 26, 1970
- Testimonials and Case Histories: Results of the Crosser Amendments to the Railroad Retirement Act (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Baltimore and Ohio Employees Magazine, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  November, 1914
- The New York Central Railroad Company. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Instructions for Conductors and Others Concerned Pertaining to Free Travel and Passes
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for American Railway Association, 1910-1914 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Ann Arbor Railroad Company, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Association of American Railroads, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Company, 1924-1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, 1927-1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Central of Georgia Railway, 1944-1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company, 1927-1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Chicago & Eastern Illinois Railroad Company, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Chicago and North Western Railway Company, 1936-1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Chicago and Burlington Railroad Company, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Chicago Car Interchange, 1912-1934 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Cincinnati, Hamilton, and Dayton Railroad Company, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Delaware, Lackawanna and Western Railroad Company, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Detroit and Toledo Shoreline, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Erie Railroad Company, 1920-1950 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Grand Trunk Railway Company of Canada, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Hocking Valley Railway, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Illinois Central Gulf Railroad Company, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Kentucky & Indiana Terminal Railroad Company, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Lehigh Valley Railroad Company, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Minneapolis, St. Paul & Sault Ste. Marie Railroad Company, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Missouri Pacific Railroad Company, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for New York Central Railroad Company, 1926-1956 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for New York, Chicago & St. Louis Railroad, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Nickel Plate (Railroad)-- (New York, Chicago & St. Louis Railroad), 1924-1954 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Norfolk and Western Railway Company, 1954-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Pennsylvania Railroad, 1929-1943 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Pere Marquette, 1924-1944 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Pittsburgh & West Virginia Railway Company, 1920-1949 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books, 1913-1927 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Spokane, Portland, and Seattle Railway, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Toledo, Peoria & Western Railroad, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Toledo Terminal Railroad Company, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Wabash Railway Company, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Rules and interpretations and misc. books for Wheeling and Lake Erie Railway Company, 1917-1945 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Time tables for the following railroads, 1951-1972 (Box 4, Folder All)
  Pennsylvania Railroad - Western Region; Pennsylvania Railroad - Northwestern Region; Pennsylvania Railroad - Buckeye Region; Pennsylvania Railroad - Lake Region; Penn Central - Western Region
- Time tables and schedules for the following railroads, 1923-1979 (Box 5, Folder All)
  The Cleveland & Canton Railroad; The Cleveland, Canton and Southern Railroad; Canadian National Railways; Union Pacific; AMTRAK; Kansas City Southern Lines; Southern Railway System; Railroad Men's Time Book; Erie-Lackawanna; Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company; Toledo, Peoria & Western Railroad Company; Houston, Belt and Terminal Railway Company; Kentucky & Indiana Terminal Railroad Company; Nickel Plate Road (New York, Chicago & St. Louis Railroad Company); Illinois Central; Baltimore & Ohio Railroad; Pennsylvania Railroad; New York Central - Western Area; Missouri Pcific Lines; Penn Central - East/West
- Time table (leather bound) for the Northern Pacific Railway Company, 1932 (Box 6, Folder All)